Guide to the Eric Oldberg Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Eric Oldberg papers
1927-1981
MS 1610
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The papers include correspondence and photographs which document the medical career of Eric Oldberg. The papers focus on Oldberg's work with Harvey Cushing.
Oldberg, Eric, 1901-1986
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Eric Oldberg Papers consist of correspondence and photographs which document the early medical career of Eric Oldberg. The papers focus on Oldberg's years training under Harvey Cushing and on Cushing's continuing influence on Oldberg's career. The papers include drafts of papers by Oldberg from his Oxford studies (folder 13) and a copy of the surgical schedule from the Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, listing operations in which he assited Cushing (folder 15). Mrs. Eric Oldberg gave her husband's papers to the Yale Medical Historical Library after her husband's death. The papers were transferred to the Manuscripts and Archives Department in 1991.
Biographical / Historical
Eric Oldberg was born in 1901. He attended Northwestern University and received all his academic degrees there, including an M.D. and Ph.D. In 1928 he went to Boston to receive further medical training at the Peter Bent Brigham Hospital under Harvey Cushing. He received a Guggenheim Traveling Fellowship and studied at the Kaiser Wilhelm University in Germany and at Oxford University in England. For many years he served as professor and head of the Department of Neurology and Neurological Surgery at the University of Illinois College of Medicine in Chicago. He retired in 1971.
Medicine; Cushing, Harvey, 1869-1939; Oldberg, Eric, 1901-1986; Stanton, Madeline E. (Madeline Earle)
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, general, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, general, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, general, 1932-1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bailey, Percival, 1928-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cairns, Sir Hugh and Barbara, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cushing, Harvey, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cushing, Harvey, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cushing, Harvey, 1935-1939, 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eisenhardt, Louise, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fulton, John, 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hedblom, Carl A., 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Liddell, Pat, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - McLean, A.J., 1929-1938 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Peters, G. Gorham, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sherrington, Sir Charles Scott, 1931-1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stanton, Madeline, 1928-1939, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, 1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)